= 权力的游戏 第1季第8集 =
剑之尖端
首播时间: 2011年6月5日
== 翻译: freesand ==
(君临城)
Subtitles downloaded from Podnapisi.NET
(鹰巢城)
(临冬城)
(绝境长城)
(维斯多斯拉克)
原著: 乔治马丁
( Theme music playing )
= Game of Thrones 1x07 =
The Pointy End
Original Air Date on June 5, 2011
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
( Wooden swords clacking )
左上, 左下.
Yah! Left high, left low.
( Swords clanging )
右下, 右刺.
Right low, lunge right.
你要是弄坏什么东西, 修女会要了我的命.
You break anything, the Septa will have my head.
怎么...
- What is-- - ( Screaming )
你妹妹很清楚我们今天要走.
Your sister knew perfectly well we were to leave today.
- 她怎么会忘记... - 她没有忘记.
- How she could forget-- - She didn't forget.
她跟她的舞蹈老师在一起. 每天早上都是.
She's with her dancing master. She's with him every morning.
她总是带着满身瘀伤回来. 她真是笨手笨脚.
She always comes back with scrapes and bruises. She's so clumsy.
别出声!
- ( Swords clanging ) - Hush!
回你的房间去.
Go back to your room.
插上门闩
Bar the doors
绝不要给不认识的人开门.
and do not open them for anyone you do not know.
- 怎么了? 出什么事了? - 照我说的做.
- What is it? What's happening? - Do as I told you.
快跑!
Run!
这边!
Man: This way!
( Reaming )
左, 右. 右!
Left, right. Rah!
现在你死了.
Now you are dead.
你说的是右边,
You said right,
但你打的却是左边.
but you went left.
结果你是个死女孩了.
And now you are a dead girl.
可是你骗人了.
Only 'cause you lied.
我的舌头骗人了. 可我的眼睛...
My tongue lied. My eyes
说的是真话. 只是你没看见.
shouted the truth. You were not seeing.
我明明看了, 但你...
I was so. I watched, but you--
看了不等于看见了, 死女孩.
watching is not seeing, dead girl.
只有看见, 只有真正的洞察,
The seeing, the true seeing,
才是剑术的精髓.
that is the heart of swordplay.
( Door opens )
艾莉亚史塔克, 跟我们走.
Arya Stark, come with us.
你父亲要见你.
Your father wants to see you.
可是为什么...
And why is it
艾德大人会派兰尼斯特家的人...
that Lord Eddard is sending Lannister men
而不是他自己的手下来呢? 我很好奇.
in place of his own? I am wondering.
别不识好歹, 舞蹈老师.
Mind your place, dancing master.
此事与你无关.
This is no concern of yours.
我父亲才不会派你们来呢.
My father wouldn't send you.
而且我也不想跟你们走.
And I don't have to go with you if I don't want.
抓住她.
( Laughs ) Take her.
你们是人还是蛇, 居然威胁一个小孩子?
Are you men or snakes, that you would threaten a child?
给我滚开, 矮家伙.
Get out of my way, little man.
我是西利欧佛瑞尔...
I am Syrio Forel...
外国杂种.
Foreign bastard.
...你跟我讲话要放尊重点.
...And you will be speaking to me with more respect.
宰了这布拉佛斯人, 把那女孩抓来.
Kill the Braavosi. Bring the girl.
小艾莉亚, 今天我们的舞蹈课至此为止.
Arya child, we are done with dancing for the day.
跑去找你父亲吧.
Run to your father.
该死的东西.
- Bloody oafs. - ( Sword rings )
快走, 艾莉亚.
Be gone now, Arya.
跟我一起走. 快跑.
Come with me. Run.
布拉佛斯的首席剑士从不临阵脱逃.
The first sword of Braavos does not run.
记不记得我们应该
( Wood clatters )
What do we say
怎么对死神说话?
to the God of death?
"今天不行."
Not today.
快走.
Go.
( Lannister men moaning )
- ( Swords ringing ) - ( Men screaming )
今天不行. 今天不行.
Not today. Not today.
( Gasps )
你不要过来.
Stay away from me.
我要告诉我父亲.
I'll tell my father.
我要... 我要告诉王后.
I'll-- I'll tell the Queen.
你以为是谁派我来的?
( Chuckles ) Who do you think sent me?
( Horses neigh )
缝衣针.
Needle.
原来她在这儿.
There she is.
- 你想要什么? - 我要抓你, 小狼女.
- What do you want? - I want you, wolf girl.
- 过来. - 不要过来.
- Come here. - Leave me be.
我父亲是首相. 他会奖赏你的.
My father's a lord. He'll reward you.
会奖赏我的是王后!
She'll reward me-- the Queen!
走开!
- Stay away! - ( Gasps )
( Door clanging, creaking )
史塔克大人, 你一定渴了.
Lord Stark, you must be thirsty.
瓦里斯.
Varys.
我向你保证里面没有下毒.
I promise you it isn't poisoned.
为什么没人肯信任太监呢?
Why is it no one ever trusts the eunuch?
不太多, 大人.
Not so much, My Lord.
如果我是你的话, 我会留下一点.
I would save the rest, if I were you.
藏好它. 在这地牢里常有人被渴死.
Hide it. Men have been known to die of thirst in these cells.
我的女儿们怎么样了?
What about my daughters?
小的那个看来已经逃出了红堡.
The younger one seems to have escaped the castle.
连我的小小鸟们都找不到她.
Even my little birds cannot find her.
- 珊莎呢? - 依然是乔佛里的未婚妻.
- And Sansa? - Still engaged to Joffrey.
瑟曦会把她留在身边. 但你家其他的人...
Cersei will keep her close. The rest of your household though--
全死了, 我感到很痛心.
all dead, it grieves me to say.
我讨厌看到流血.
I do so hate the sight of blood.
我的手下被屠杀时你却袖手旁观.
You watched my men being slaughtered and did nothing.
我只能那样, 大人.
And would again, My Lord.
我既没武器, 又没盔甲, 还被兰尼斯特的武士团团围住.
I was unarmed, unarmored and surrounded by Lannister swords.
你看我象个大英雄吗?
When you look at me do you see a hero?
究竟是什么疯狂念头让你去告诉王后...
What madness led you to tell the Queen
说你知道乔佛里的真实身世?
you had learned the truth about Joffrey's birth?
仁慈的疯狂念头.
The madness of mercy.
希望她能保住她孩子们的性命.
That she might save her children.
啊, 孩子们.
Ah, the children.
受苦的总是那些无辜者.
It is always the innocents who suffer.
杀死国王的不是那袋酒, 也不是那只野猪.
It wasn't the wine that killed Robert, nor the boar.
酒令他反应迟缓, 野猪撕开了他的肚子,
The wine slowed him down and the boar ripped him open,
但是真正杀死国王的却是你的仁慈.
but it was your mercy that killed the King.
我想你知道自己在劫难逃吧, 艾德大人?
I trust you know you are a dead man, Lord Eddard?
王后不会杀我.
The Queen can't kill me.
凯特还抓着她的弟弟.
Cat holds her brother.
可惜不是她爱的那个弟弟.
The wrong brother sadly.
而且这会儿也跑了.
And lost to her.
你夫人让小恶魔从她的指缝里钻了出去.
Your wife has let the Imp slip through her fingers.
倘若真是这样,
If that's true,
那快快割了我的喉咙, 做个了结.
then slit my throat and be done with it.
今天不会, 大人.
Not today, My Lord.
告诉我, 瓦里斯.
Tell me something, Varys.
你究竟是为谁服务?
Who do you truly serve?
为了国家, 大人.
The Realm, My Lord.
总得有人为国家服务.
Someone must.
( Door creaks, clangs )
这是奥瑟, 肯定没错.
It's Othor, without a doubt.
另外那个是杰佛佛花, 大人,
The other one is Jafer Flowers, My Lord,
他的一只手被狼咬掉了.
less the hand the wolf tore off.
有班扬或他手下其他人的踪迹吗?
Any sign of Benjen or the rest of his party?
只有这两个, 大人.
Just these two, My Lord.
我看他们死了有一阵子了.
Been dead awhile, I'd say.
- 嗯. - 可是气味...
- Mmm. - The smell.
( Sniffs )
怎么气味?
What smell?
没有气味.
There is none.
如果他们死了很久, 怎么还没腐烂?
If they'd be dead for a long time, wouldn't there be rot?
我们烧了他们吧.
We should burn them.
雪诺说得没错, 大人. 烧掉尸体吧.
Snow's not wrong, My Lord. Fire will do for them.
野人的处理方式.
The Wildling way.
我要先让伊蒙师傅检查一下这些尸体.
I want Maester Aemon to examine them first.
你也许是个懦夫, 塔利,
You may be a coward, Tarly,
但人倒是不笨.
but you're not stupid.
- 把他们弄进去. - 照他说的做.
- Get them inside. - You heard him.
总司令,
Lord Commander,
伊蒙师傅正在等你过去...
Maester Aemon awaits you in his chambers--
君临城来了一只渡鸦.
a raven from King's Landing.
快移出去.
Come on, move 'em out.
给我倒杯酒, 雪诺,
Bring me a horn of ale, Snow,
再给你自己也倒一杯.
and pour one for yourself.
国王死了.
The King is dead.
我父亲有什么消息?
Is there any word of my father?
坐下.
Sit.
史塔克大人...
Lord Stark has been
被控叛国.
charged with treason.
他们说他与劳勃的弟弟共谋
They say he conspired with Robert's brothers
阻止乔佛里王子继位.
to deny the throne to Prince Joffrey.
我希望你别打算做任何傻事.
I hope you're not thinking of doing anything stupid.
如今你的职责所在是这里.
Your duty lies here now.
我的妹妹也在君临.
My sisters were in King's Landing too.
我相信她们定会...
I'm sure they'll be
受到妥善照顾.
treated gently.
你的父亲犯下了严重的叛国罪.
Your father has proved to be an awful traitor, dear.
劳勃国王尸骨未寒
King Robert's body was still warm
艾德大人就密谋夺取乔佛里的王位.
when Lord Eddard began plotting to steal Joffrey's rightful throne.
他绝不会做这种事.
He wouldn't do that.
他知道我有多爱乔佛里. 他绝不会.
He knows how much I love Joffrey. He wouldn't.
求求您, 王后陛下, 这一定是误会.
Please, Your Grace, there's been a mistake.
找我父亲过来. 他会向您解释... 他是国王的朋友.
Send for my father. He'll tell you-- the King was his friend.
亲爱的珊莎, 你是完全无辜的. 我们都明白.
Sansa sweetling, you are innocent of any wrong. We know that.
但你毕竟是个叛国者的女儿.
Yet you are the daughter of a traitor.
我怎么敢让你嫁给我儿子呢?
How can I allow you to marry my son?
叛国者的种必有背叛之性...
Pycelle: A child born of a traitor's seed
不适合陪伴我们的国王.
is no fit consort for our King.
眼下她是个可爱的好孩子, 陛下,
She is a sweet thing now, Your Grace,
可十年以后谁知道...
but in 10 years who knows
她会否同样犯下背叛罪行呢?
what treasons she may hatch?
不, 我不是. 我一定会成为他的好妻子.
No, I'm not. I'll be a good wife to him, you'll see.
我会成为象您一样的好王后, 我保证. 我绝不会做任何错事.
I'll be a Queen just like you, I promise. I won't hatch anything.
这孩子是无辜的, 陛下.
The girl is innocent, Your Grace.
应该给她一个机会, 来证明她的忠诚.
She should be given a chance to prove her loyalty.
( Huffs )
可爱的小鸽子, 你得写信给凯特琳夫人
Little dove, you must write to Lady Catelyn
以及你的大哥, 他叫什么名字?
and your brother, the eldest, what's his name?
罗柏.
Robb.
你父亲被捕的消息很快就会传到他那里.
Word of your father's arrest will reach him soon, no doubt.
所以最好由你来告诉他.
Best it comes from you.
如果你想救你父亲,
If you would help your father,
就必须敦促你大哥维护王国的和平.
urge your brother to keep the King's peace.
叫他前来君临向乔佛里宣誓效忠.
Tell him to come to King's Landing and swear his fealty to Joffrey.
或许... 如果我可以见见我父亲, 和他谈谈...
If-- if I could see my father, talk to him about--
你太令我失望了, 孩子.
You disappoint me, child.
我们已经告诉过你令尊的罪行.
We have told you of your father's treason.
为何你还想要见一个叛徒?
Why would you want to speak to a traitor?
我只是想知道...
I only meant that--
他会被如何处置?
what will happen to him?
- 这要看情况. - 看什么... 情况?
- That depends. - On-- on what?
看你的大哥...
On your brother.
还有你会如何做.
And on you.
叛国?
Treason?
这信是珊莎写的?
Sansa wrote this?
是你妹妹的笔迹, 但其实是王后的言辞.
It is your sister's hand, but the Queen's words.
召你去君临向新王宣誓效忠.
You are summoned to King's Landing to swear fealty to the new King.
乔佛里囚禁了我父亲, 还想要我对他效忠?
Joffrey puts my father in chains, now he wants his ass kissed?
这是王室的谕令, 大人.
This is a royal command, My Lord.
- 如果你拒绝服从... - 我不会拒绝.
- If you should refuse to obey-- - I won't refuse.
既然国王陛下召我去君临,
His Grace summons me to King's Landing,
那我会去君临的.
I'll go to King's Landing.
但不是一个人去.
But not alone.
立刻召集封臣.
Call the banners.
召集全部吗, 大人?
All of them, My Lord?
他们全都发过誓要保卫我父亲, 是吧?
They've all sworn to defend my father, have they not?
是的.
They have.
现在就让我们看看他们能否信守誓言吧.
Now we see what their words are worth.
好吧.
Yeah.
你感到害怕吗?
Are you afraid?
我是感到害怕.
I must be.
很好.
Good.
为什么这很好?
Why is that good?
这说明你并不愚蠢.
It means you're not stupid.
( Cawing )
你在清早就收到这封信了?
You've had this since dawn?
信是发给我的, 而不是给你的.
He sent it to me, not you.
我只是出于礼貌才给你看.
I've only shown it to you as a courtesy.
出于礼貌?!
A courtesy?!
我的丈夫被囚禁.
My husband has been taken prisoner.
我的儿子准备宣战.
My son intends to declare war.
宣战?
A war?
你儿子要对兰尼斯特家开战?
Your son against the Lannisters?
你应该赶去他那里. 叫他保持耐心.
You should go to him. Teach him patience.
奈德在地牢里等死, 你还说要保持耐心?
Ned rots in a dungeon and you speak of patience?
他是你的姐夫!
He is your brother by law!
难道家族对你来说毫无意义吗?
Does family mean nothing to you?
家族对我来说意味着一切.
Family means everything to me.
我绝不会拿罗宾的性命来冒险
And I will not risk Robin's life
卷入另一场跟你丈夫有关的战争.
to get caught up in another of your husband's wars.
- 我饿了. - 安静, 亲爱的.
- I'm hungry. - Hush now, darling.
你刚刚吃过呀.
You just ate.
那你不会支持我们了? 你是这个意思吗?
You will not support us then? Do I understand you correctly?
- 可我就是饿了! - 快了, 亲爱的, 快了.
- But I'm hungry! - Soon, love, soon.
这儿永远欢迎你, 姐姐.
You're always welcome here, sister.
但如果你想要我派兵离开艾林谷去参战...
But if you're asking me to send men from the Vale to fight--
我就是想要你这样做.
That is what I ask.
亲爱的. 你该洗澡了.
Go on, sweet. Time for your bath.
洗过澡我就喂你吃.
I'll feed you after.
如果你担心你儿子的安危...
If you fear for the safety of your son--
我当然担心我儿子的安危!
Of course I fear for the safety of my son!
你当我是白痴吗?
Are you an idiot?
他们谋杀了我丈夫.
They killed my husband.
你说他们还把你儿子从窗口抛下去.
You say they shoved your boy from a window.
那些人什么都干得出来.
These people will do anything.
所以我们必须阻止他们.
And that is why we have to stop them.
谷地的骑士将留在谷地
The knights of the Vale will stay in the Vale
他们属于这里, 他们得保护他们的领主.
where they belong, to protect their Lord.
( Whistling a tune )
你能不能闭嘴?
Will you shut up?
这一带到处是山地部落.
There's hill tribes all around here.
如果我真的要死了,
If I'm going to die,
我宁愿哼着歌去死.
it may as well be with a song in my heart.
我可以抢走你的食物并把你丢在这里.
I should just take your food and leave you here.
嗯? 那时候你会怎样?
Eh? What would you do then?
八成会被饿死.
Starve, most likely.
你觉得我不会这么做, 是吗?
You don't think I'd do it, do you?
你想要什么, 波隆? 金子? 女人?
What do you want, Bronn? Gold? Women?
多金的女人?
Golden women?
跟着我, 你要什么有什么,
Stick with me and you'll have them all,
只要有我在, 你很快就能得到你想要的.
for as long as I'm around and not for a moment longer.
你知道这一点.
But you knew that.
所以你才会如此勇敢地为维护我的荣誉而出战.
That is why you so valiantly took up arms to defend my honor.
很公平.
Fair enough.
但别指望我会对你卑躬屈膝...
But don't go looking for me to bend the knee
对你说话时满口老爷大人.
and "My Lord" you every time you take a shit.
我不当你的仆人, 也不当你的朋友.
I'm not your toady and I'm not your friend.
但我珍视你的友谊,
Though I would treasure your friendship,
我主要看重你杀人的身手.
I'm mainly interested in your facility with murder.
而要是哪天真有人引诱你出卖我,
And if the day ever comes when you're tempted to sell me out,
请你记住:
remember this:
不管他们出价多少, 我都能出更多给你.
Whatever their price, I'll beat it.
我很爱惜我这条命.
I like living.
( Whistles )
提利昂.
- ( Rustling ) - ( Bronn whispers ) Tyrion.
Tyrion.
提利昂.
( Birds chirp, flutter )
过来一起烤烤火吧.
Come, share our fire.
再尝尝我们的山羊肉.
Help yourselves to our goat.
当你去见你的神的时候, 告诉他们
When you meet your Gods, you tell them
是石鸦部落的多夫之子夏嘎...
Shagga Son of Dolf
送你上路的.
of the Stone Crows sent you.
我是兰尼斯特部落的泰温之子提利昂.
I am Tyrion son of Tywin of Clan Lannister.
你想要怎么个死法, 泰温之子提利昂?
How would you like to die, Tyrion son of Tywin?
我想活到八十岁死在自己的床上
In my own bed, at the age of 80
喝饱一肚子酒, 还有个姑娘在下面给我吹萧.
with a bellyful of wine and a girl's mouth around my cock.
( Laughing )
( All laughing )
把那半人抓起来.
Take the half man.
可以让他给孩子们跳舞. 把另外那家伙宰了.
He can dance for the children. Kill the other one.
不不不不不!
No no no no no!
我的家族既有钱又有势.
My-- my House is rich and powerful.
只要你们保我们平安出山,
If you see us through these mountains,
我父亲赏你们的金子会多到可以拿来洗澡.
my father will shower you with gold.
我们才不相信半人的承诺.
We have no use for a half man's promises.
我虽然只是半个人, 但至少我有勇气面前敌人.
Half a man maybe, but at least I have the courage to face my enemies.
石鸦部落的人呢?
What do the Stone Crows do?
还不是只敢躲在石头后面发抖
Hide behind rocks and shiver
当谷地的骑士经过的时候?
when the knights of the Vale ride by?
你们就只偷得到这种货色?
Are those the best weapons you could steal?
杀羊或许可以,
Good enough for killing sheep,
还得那羊乖乖认命让你们杀.
if the sheep don't fight back.
兰尼斯特家的铁匠拉出的屎都比这高级.
Lannister smiths shit better steel.
你以为你能用你的小零碎换你的命?
You think you can win us over with your trinkets?
这小零碎比你们部落的所有东西都更值钱.
That trinket is worth more than everything your tribe owns.
如果你肯帮我们, 多夫之子夏嘎,
But if you help us, Shagga Son of Dolf,
我不止会给你小零碎.
I will not give you trinkets.
我会给你这个.
I will give you this.
什么 "这个"?
What is "this"?
整个艾林谷.
The Vale of Arryn.
艾林谷的领主们一直在欺压山地部落.
The Lords of the Vale have always spat upon the hill tribes.
艾林谷的领主们想要我死.
The Lords of the Vale want me dead.
我想是时候让谷地换一批新领主了.
I believe it is time for new Lords of the Vale.
真是难得一见的人物...
Ser Alliser: Now there's a rare sight--
不但是个野种, 还是个叛国者的野种呢.
not only a bastard, but a traitor's bastard.
- 琼恩, 不要! - 琼恩, 住手, 把刀放下!
- Jon, no! - Jon, stop, put it down!
血统决定善恶.
Blood will always tell.
你会被吊死的, 野种.
You'll hang for this, bastard.
我告诉过你别做傻事.
I told you not to do anything stupid.
你被关禁闭了. 去吧.
You're confined to quarters. Go.
( Barking, whining )
白灵, 怎么了?
Ghost, what's wrong?
外面出什么事了?
Is something out there?
( Whining growls )
( Snarling )
( Growling )
总司令?
Commander?
( Barks, whines )
待在这里.
Stay.
喂?
Hello?
是谁?
Who's there?
( Whines )
总司令大人?
- Lord Commander? - ( Door slams )
( Barking )
( Growling )
雪诺?
Mormont: Snow?
总司令!
Commander!
( Yelps )
快走, 快走!
Move move!
( Snarling, screaming )
( Grunts )
( Screaming, snarling continue )
他们在干什么?
What did they do?
(羊人最适合当奴隶.)
( Rakharo speaking Dothraki )
(卓戈卡奥会把他们送给奴隶贩子.)
(奴隶贩子会送给我们金钱.)
(还有丝绸和钢铁.)
我以为多斯拉克人不信赖金钱.
Daenerys: I thought the Dothraki didn't believe in money.
金钱可以雇船, 公主,
Gold to hire ships, Princess,
乘船才能去维斯特洛.
ships to sail to Westeros.
( Louder screaming )
乔拉, 叫他们住手.
Jorah, make them stop.
- 卡丽熙? - 你听到我的命令了.
- Khaleesi? - You heard me.
这些人为卡奥流血卖命, 如今该他们取得奖赏了.
These men have shed blood for their Khal. Now they claim their rewards.
(她是个羊女, 卡丽煕.)
( Rakharo speaking )
(我们的战士上她是看得起她.)
(要是她的哭嚎冒犯了卡丽煕.)
(我去把她的舌头割了.)
公主, 你的心肠很软,
Princess, you have a gentle heart,
但战争就是这个样子.
but this is how it's always been.
我的心肠并不软, 爵士.
I do not have a gentle heart, Ser.
(照我的命令办, 否则卡奥惟你是问)
(住手!)
( Rakharo speaks )
(吾血之血. 她是我的!)
Kash qoy qoyi thira disse. Me qorasokh anni!
- 来吧. - (她是我抓到的!)
- Come. - Man: Anha afichak mae m'arakhoon!
(你小心一点.)
( Speaks Dothraki )
你要怎么处置她?
What do you want done with them?
把她带到我这儿来. 还有那些女人.
Bring her to me. And those women there.
您没法把她们全都收为己有, 公主.
You cannot claim them all, Princess.
我能,
I can,
我就要这样做.
and I will.
(操!)
Man: Me Fati!
(卡丽熙抢了我的战利品,)
Khaleesi vazha anhaan qorasokh anni,
(本该是让我骑的羊女!)
ch'anha afichak mae m'arakhoon anni!
(等我见到她,)
Drogo: Me vastoe hatif anni;
(我会问一下这件事.)
ahhazaan yer Nemo vacchaki.
(我生命中的月亮,)
(马戈说你抢了他的战利品.)
(一个本该让他骑的羊人之女.)
(告诉我是怎么回事.)
(马戈说的是实话, 我的日和星.)
(今天我是收了许多羊女...)
(不让她们被人骑...)
(战争就是这样.)
(现在这些女人是奴隶...)
(...随我们高兴摆布.)
(那我高兴让她们平安.)
(若你的战士要骑她们, 就要将她们收作妻子.)
(马会和羊交配吗?)
(马和羊都是龙的食物!)
(你是个外族人.)
(你无权命令我.)
(我是卡丽熙, 我有权命令你.)
( Drogo snickers )
(看她变得多凶猛?)
(这是因为她怀着我的儿子, 骑着世界的骏马,)
(让她充满火焰.)
(我听明白了.)
(马戈, 找别地方去发泄吧.)
( Spits )
(听从外族女人的卡奥还算是什么卡奥.)
(奥霍斯.)
( Drogo grunts ) Ohos.
(让开.)
Os.
(我不会用火烧掉你的尸体.)
(我不会给你那样的荣耀.)
(我会让甲虫吃你的眼珠.)
(我会让蛆虫爬满你的肺.)
(我会让雨水落在你腐烂的皮肤上...)
(...直到你只剩下一把骨头.)
(你要先杀得死我才行.)
(你就要死了.)
( Gasps )
(我的日和星受伤了.)
(只是破了点皮...)
(...我生命中的月亮.)
(医者在哪儿?)
(让飞虫咬了一口而已.)
(我可以帮伟大的骑马战士疗伤.)
( Woman speaking Dothraki )
( Gasps )
(卡奥不需要跟羊交配的女人帮忙.)
(她是我的人, 让她说.)
谢谢您, 银发夫人.
Thank you, silver lady.
你是谁?
Who are you?
我叫弥丽马兹笃尔. 是这座神庙的女祭司.
I am named Mirri Maz Duur. I was the Godswife of this Temple.
(巫魔女.)
( Spits )
我母亲是从前的女祭司.
My mother was Godswife here before me.
她教会我如何调制圣烟和圣膏.
She taught me how to make healing smokes and ointments.
所有人类都是同一群羔羊, 这是我们的信仰.
All men are of one flock, so my people believe.
至高牧神派我到世上医治他的...
The Great Shepherd sent me to Earth to heal his--
(巫魔女太多话了. 会毒害耳朵.)
不论是羔羊或是狮子,
lamb or lion,
他的伤口必须立刻清洗缝针
his wound must be washed and sewn
不然会化脓的.
or it will fester.
(让她给你清洗伤口吧, 我的日和星...)
(看见你流血让我心痛.)
( Men chatting, eating )
三十年来我杀死过...
For 30 years I've been making corpses
无数敌人, 小子.
out of men, boy.
我最适合率领前锋.
I'm the man you want leading the Vanguard.
盖伯特葛洛佛才该率领前锋.
Galbart Glover will lead the Van.
除非他妈的长城整个融化
The bloody Wall will melt
否则安伯家别想走在葛洛佛家前头.
before an Umber marches behind a Glover.
我要率领前锋
I will lead the Van
否则我就带着我的人马
or I will take my men
班师回家.
and march them home.
欢迎你这么做, 安伯大人.
You are welcome to do so, Lord Umber.
等我收拾完兰尼斯特家
And when I am done with the Lannisters
我会立刻回师北上,
I will march back North,
把你从你的城堡里抓出来
root you out of your Keep
并当成背誓者吊死.
and hang you for an oathbreaker.
背誓者, 是吗?!
Oathbreaker, is it?!
我可不会干坐着任人侮辱
I'll not sit here and swallow insults
特别是象你这种刚从泥里钻出来的小鬼, 八成连尿都还有青草气.
from a boy so green he pisses grass.
( Snarls )
( Screaming )
我父亲曾教导我必须以死刑惩戒...
My Lord father taught me it was death to bare steel
敢对主君拔剑的封臣.
- against your Liege Lord. - ( Huffs )
但我相信大琼恩只是想帮我切肉罢了.
But doubtless the Greatjon only meant to cut my meat for me.
你的肉...
Your meat...
还真他妈的硬.
is bloody tough.
( Chortles )
( All laughing )
- 怎么了? 出什么事了? - 嘘, 没什么.
- What is it? What's happened? - Shh, it's all right.
- 你要去哪儿? - 去南方. 去救父亲.
- Where are you going? - South. For father.
可现在是午夜啊.
But it's the middle of the night.
兰尼斯特家的探子无处不在.
The Lannisters have spies everywhere.
我不希望让他们知道我们已经出发.
I don't want them to know we're coming.
他们的人马比我们多.
They have more men than we do.
嗯, 是这样的.
Aye, they do.
我能和你一起去吗?
Can't I come with you?
现在我能骑马了. 你看过我骑马了.
I can ride now. You've seen me riding.
我不会再惹麻烦的, 我...
And I won't get in the way, I--
临冬城必须有史塔克家的人坐镇.
There must always be a Stark at Winterfell.
在我回来之前你就是城主.
Until I return that will be you.
我们走后你绝不能离开城堡. 明白吗?
You are not to leave the castle walls while we are gone. Do you understand?
好好听从鲁温师傅的教导. 好好照顾你的弟弟.
Listen to Maester Luwin. Look after your little brother.
我会的.
I will.
我有时间就会写信回来,
I'll send letters whenever I can,
但如果你很久没收到我的信,
but if you don't hear from me,
也不要担心.
don't be scared.
我会回来的.
Until I return.
你躲在那儿多久了?
How long have you been hiding out there?
罗柏会找你道别.
Robb will be looking for you to say goodbye.
他们全都走了.
They've all gone away.
他们很快就会回来. 罗柏会救出父亲
They'll be back soon. Robb will free father
他们会和母亲一道回来.
and they'll come back with mother.
不, 他们不会.
No, they won't.
请你们务必看顾罗柏.
Bran: Please watch over Robb.
也请你们看顾临冬城所所有人马.
And watch over all the other men from Winterfell.
还有, 还有席恩.
And Theon too, I suppose.
你听见了吗, 孩子?
You hear them, boy?
旧神正在回答你.
The Old Gods are answering you.
你在这里做什么?
What are you doing here?
他们也是我的神.
They're my Gods too.
在长城之外, 他们是惟一的真神.
Beyond the Wall, they're the only Gods.
即便奴隶也可以祈祷.
Even slaves are allowed to pray.
你可不是奴隶.
You're not a slave.
嗯, 你的朋友确实曾经拿刀抵住我的喉咙.
Well, your friend did put a knife to my throat.
我不是在抱怨, 小领主,
I'm not complaining, Little Lord,
只是说出事实.
just telling truths.
你说听见神说话是什么意思?
What did you mean about hearing the Gods?
你向他们祈求,
You asked them,
而他们正在回答.
they're answering you.
嘘.
Shh.
竖起耳朵.
Open your ears.
( Leaves rustling )
不过是风声.
It's only the wind.
你以为这风是谁送来的?
Who do you think sends the wind
如果不是诸神的话?
if not the Gods?
他们能看到你, 孩子.
They see you, boy.
他们也能听到你说话.
They hear you.
( Sighs )
在你哥哥要去的地方, 他们无法帮他.
Your brother will get no help from them where he's going.
旧神在南方没有力量.
The Old Gods have no power in the South.
那儿的鱼梁木早已被砍伐一空.
The Weirwoods there were all cut down a long time ago.
没有眼睛, 他们如何看顾你哥哥呢?
How can they watch when they have no eyes?
( Running footsteps )
嗯, 真是个大块头.
( Osha giggles ) Well, there's a big man.
我敢说他有巨人的血统.
He has giants' blood in him or I'm the Queen.
回去找你的衣服, 阿多.
Go back and find your clothes, Hodor.
去穿衣服吧.
- ( Laughs ) - Go dress.
阿多.
Hodor.
长城之外真的有巨人吗?
Are there really giants beyond the Wall?
有巨人, 还有比巨人更可怕的生物.
Giants and worse than giants.
我跟你哥哥说过,
I tried telling your brother,
他走错方向了.
he's marching the wrong way.
所有的人马, 他们应该去北方, 孩子.
All these swords, they should be going North, boy.
北方, 不是南方!
North, not south!
寒风已然吹起.
The cold winds are rising.
( Leaves rustling )
他们被异鬼做了手脚.
They were touched by White Walkers.
所以他们才会回来.
That's why they came back.
所以他们的眼睛才会变成蓝色.
That's why their eyes turned blue.
只有火能阻止他们.
Only fire will stop them.
你怎么知道的?
How do you know that?
我从书上看到的...
I read about it in a book--
伊蒙师傅的图书馆里的一本非常古老的书.
a very old book in Maester Aemon's library.
那本书还说了些什么?
What else did the book say?
异鬼
The White Walkers
在冰层之下沉睡了数千年.
sleep beneath the ice for thousands of years.
当他们苏醒的时候...
And when they wake up--
当他们苏醒的时候会怎样?
And when they wake up, what?
我希望长城足够高.
I hope The Wall is high enough.
( Men chattering )
是夏雪, 夫人.
Summer snows, My Lady.
罗柏马带来了北境的人马.
Robb's brought the North with him.
河间地的领主们正在败退
The River Lords are falling back
詹姆兰尼斯特在后面穷追不舍.
with Jaime Lannister at their heels.
而泰温大人正带着另一支兰尼斯特军队从南方进逼.
And Lord Tywin is bringing around a second Lannister army from the South.
我们的斥候报告说其规模比弑君者的更庞大.
Our scouts confirm it's even larger than the Kingslayer's.
管他一支还是两支军队, 北境之王...
One army or two, the Kings in the North
能够打垮十倍优势的敌人.
threw back hosts 10 times as large.
母亲!
Mother!
你气色很好.
You look well.
凯特琳夫人, 在此动乱时刻见到您真是高兴.
Lady Catelyn, you're a welcome sight in these troubled times.
我们没想到会在这里见到您, 夫人.
We had not thought to meet you here, My Lady.
我也没想到会来这里.
I had not thought to be here.
我想单独和我儿子讲几句话.
I would speak with my son alone.
相信诸位大人能够理解.
I know you will forgive me, My Lords.
你们听见夫人说的话了! 快动身!
You heard her! Move your asses!
快点, 到外面去.
Come on, out.
你也是, 葛雷乔伊. 你他妈的耳聋了吗?
You too, Greyjoy. Are you bloody deaf?
不要担心, 夫人.
Have no fear, My Lady.
我们会拿剑拥穿泰温兰尼斯特的屁眼...
We'll shove our swords up Tywin Lannister's bunghole
然后打下红堡救出奈德.
and then it's on to the Red Keep to free Ned.
- 你这老鬼头, 罗德利克. - 大琼恩.
- You old devil, Rodrik. - Jon.
你的功夫还没荒废, 是吗?
You're not wasting away, are you?
我还清楚地记得你出生那天的样子...
I remember the day you came into this world
脸红红的, 大声哭闹.
red-faced and squalling.
现在我却看到你率领着一支大军上战场.
And now I find you leading a host to war.
- 没别人了. - 没别人?
- There was no one else. - No one?
我刚才见到的那些人是谁?
Who were those men I saw here?
- 他们都不是史塔克. - 他们都身经百战.
- None of them are Starks. - All of them are seasoned in battle.
如果你想把我送回临冬城...
If you think you can send me back to Winterfell--
哦, 我真希望能这么做.
Oh, would that I could.
我收到了...
There was...
一封信.
a letter.
珊莎写来的.
From Sansa.
你的意思是王后写来的.
From the Queen, you mean.
- 上面没有提到艾莉亚. - 确实没有.
- There's no mention of Arya. - No.
你带来多少人?
How many men do you have?
一万八千.
18,000.
如果我去君临向乔佛里屈膝下跪...
If I go to King's Landing and bend my knee to Joffrey--
不, 那样你将永远无法离开.
you would never be allowed to leave. No.
我们最大的希望... 或者说惟一的希望...
Our best hope-- our only hope--
便是你能在战场上击败对手.
is that you can defeat them in the field.
如果我战败?
And if I lose?
你知道坦格利安家孩子们的下场吗...
Do you know what happened to the Targaryen children
- 当君临城陷的时候? - 他们在睡梦中被屠杀.
- when the Mad King fell? - They were butchered in their sleep.
是泰温兰尼斯特下的命令.
On the orders of Tywin Lannister.
多年的时光并没有使他变仁慈一点.
And the years have not made him kinder.
如果你战败,
If you lose,
你的父亲会死,
your father dies,
你的妹妹们也会死,
your sisters die,
我们都会死.
we die.
好吧, 那事情就简单了.
Well, that makes it simple then.
我想是这样.
I suppose it does.
现在最好由波隆和我两个过去.
From here it might be best if Bronn and I continue alone.
对泰温之子提利昂来说最好.
Best for Tyrion son of Tywin.
对我们来说可不好.
Not best for me.
如果半人背叛我们,
If the half man betrays us,
多夫之子夏嘎就会剁掉他的命根子...
Shagga Son of Dolf will cut off his manhood--
拿去喂山羊, 我知道.
and feed it to the goats, yes.
那好吧.
All right then.
我要去见我父亲了.
Time to meet my father.
- 提利昂. - 叔叔.
- Tyrion. - Uncle.
父亲.
Father.
看来关于你已死的传言不攻自破了.
The rumors of your demise were unfounded.
真抱歉让您失望了.
Sorry to disappoint you.
这些是什么人...
And who are these...
你的同伴?
Companions of yours?
这位是多夫之子夏嘎,
This is Shagga Son of Dolf,
石鸦部的酋长.
Chieftain of the Stone Crows.
提魅之子提魅, 灼人部的首领.
Timett Son of Timett, ruler of the Burned Men.
这位美少女是齐克之女齐拉
This fair maid is Chella daughter of Cheyk,
黑耳部的领袖.
leader of the Black Ears.
而这位是波隆, 谁人之子来着...
And here we have Bronn son of...
你不会认识他的.
You wouldn't know him.
可否允许我为各位介绍我的父亲大人,
May I present My Lord Father,
兰尼斯特家族的泰陀斯之子泰温,
Tywin son of Tytos of House Lannister,
凯岩城主暨西境守护.
Lord of Casterly Rock and Warden of the West?
非常感谢您为我出兵打仗.
Kind of you to go to war for me.
你使我们别无选择.
You left us no choice.
这事关家族的荣誉.
The honor of the House was at stake.
你哥哥詹姆绝不会如此轻易地束手就擒的.
Your brother would never have submitted to capture so meekly.
我们确实有所不同, 詹姆和我.
We have our differences, Jaime and I.
他更勇敢. 而我更帅气.
He's braver. I'm better looking.
他满身都是荣耀.
He's been covering himself in glory.
詹姆在金牙城外击溃了三河诸侯,
Jaime smashed the River Lords at the Golden Tooth,
现在正在围攻奔流城, 凯特琳史塔克的老家.
and now lays siege to Riverrun, Catelyn Stark's homeland.
史塔克家在做什么? 艾德大人?
And the Starks? Lord Eddard?
--现在是我们的人质. 他在地牢里无法带兵打仗.
--Is our hostage. He will lead no armies from his dungeon cell.
我那美丽的姐姐是怎么说服国王
How did my sweet sister persuade the King
囚禁他亲爱的朋友奈德的?
to imprison his dear friend Ned?
劳勃拜拉席恩死了. 如今是乔佛里在君临执政.
Robert Baratheon is dead. Joffrey rules in King's Landing.
你的意思是说是我姐姐在执政.
My sister rules, you mean.
史塔克的儿子已经下令召集封臣.
Stark's son has called his banners.
- 他正带着一支大军南下. - 不过是个毛头小子.
- He moves south with a strong host. - A green boy.
等他尝到战斗的滋味就会...
One taste of battle and he'll run
夹着尾巴逃回临冬城.
back to Winterfell wi his tail between his legs.
也许吧.
Maybe.
不过那小子确实很好战.
Though the boy does have a certain belligerence.
你会喜欢他的.
You'd like him.
既然我们说到打仗的事情,
While we're on the subject of war,
我对这几位朋友做过承诺
I made promises to my friends here
而兰尼斯特有债必还.
and a Lannister always pays his debts.
我们需要三千个头盔和盾牌,
We shall require 3,000 helms and shields,
还有刀剑, 长枪,
plus swords, pikes,
护甲, 钉锤...
gorgets, maces--
如果大人同意,
if it please My Lord,
亚当爵士要我来报告, 北境军队
Ser Addam bids me report that the Northmen
已经越过了颈泽.
have crossed the neck.
小狼就要钻进狮口了.
The wolf rushes into the lion's jaws.
好吧. 凯冯, 立刻下令敲鼓集合.
So be it. Kevan, command the drummers beat assembly.
并送信给詹姆说我将前去同罗柏史塔克决战.
And send word to Jaime that I am moving against Robb Stark.
遵命, 大人.
At once, My Lord.
听说山地部落的人都是伟大的战士.
It is said that the men of the Mountain clans are great warriors.
与我一同出兵作战
Ride with me against my enemies
你们将得到我儿子承诺的一切, 甚至更多.
and you shall have all my son promised you and more.
但这个半人得跟我们一起作战.
Only if the half man fights with us.
直到我们拿到他答应的武器,
Until we hold the steel he pledged us,
这小狮子的命是我们的.
the little lion's life is ours.
斥候报告说泰温大人正在北上.
Rodrik: The scouts report Lord Tywin moves north.
我们需要凭借险要地形截住他,
We need to get him on broken ground,
使他的骑士无法发挥力量.
put his Knights at a disadvantage.
不, 我们要从他侧面绕过去
No, we need to get around him
并打破詹姆兰尼斯特对奔流城的围攻.
and break Jaime Lannister's siege of Riverrun.
这样三河诸候就会加入我们的队伍.
Do that and the River Lords will join us.
无论怎样做我们都需要先过绿叉河
To do either we need to cross the river
而孪河城是过河的惟一路线.
and the only crossing is at The Twins.
佛雷大人控制着孪河桥.
Theon: Lord Frey controls that bridge.
他是你父亲的封臣.
Your father's bannerman.
我父亲称他为 "迟到的佛雷大人"
"The late Lord Frey" my father calls him.
当年三叉戟河之战, 他在战斗结束后才现身.
At the Trident, he didn't appear until the battle was done.
不是每个人都把自己的誓言当回事的.
Some men takes their oaths more seriously than others.
( Grunting )
罗柏说得对. 我们需要那座桥.
Robb's right. We need that bridge.
那么该怎么办?
So what's it going to be?
我们先对付詹姆还是泰温?
Do we move against Jaime or Lord Tywin?
打扰了, 大人.
Your pardon, my lords.
我们抓住了一个兰尼斯特军的斥候.
We've captured a Lannister scout.
别担心, 小伙子. 他不会活着离开这个帐篷.
Don't worry, lad. He won't b  leaving this tent with his head.
你们在哪儿发现他的?
Where did you find him?
在营地周围的树丛里.
In the brush above the encampment.
他好象正在估算人数.
He looked to be counting.
你算出来有多少人?
How high did you get?
两万. 或许更多.
20,000. Maybe more.
你不必自己动手行刑.
You don't have to do this yourself.
您父亲会理解的...
Your father would understand--
我父亲懂得仁慈, 如果不是非杀不可.
My father unrstands mercy, when there is room for it.
他也懂得荣誉...
And he understands honor...
和勇气.
and courage.
放他走吧.
Let him go.
罗柏.
Robb.
去告诉泰温大人, 凛冬将至.
( Softly ) Tell Lord Tywin Winter is coming for him.
两万北境大军正在南下, 看看他是不是真的能拉金屎.
20,000 Northerners marching south to find out if he really does shit gold.
遵命, 大人.
Yes, My Lord.
多谢, 大人.
Thank you, My Lord.
你疯了吗, 孩子?! 放他走?
Are you touched, boy?! Letting him go?
你又称我孩子了.
You call me boy again.
下去吧.
Go on.
( Growls )
喂.
Oi.
国王陛下决定...
Pycelle: It is also the wish of His Grace
尽忠职守的杰诺斯史林特,
that his loyal servant Janos Slynt,
- 都城守卫队司令... - 艾伦爵士.
- Commander of the City Watch... - Ser Aron.
立刻擢升为贵族...
...Be at once raised to the rank of Lord...
- 盖尔斯大人. - ...赐予古老的赫伦堡,
- Lord Gyles. - ...And granted the ancient seat of Harrenhal,
其子嗣将世代继承此等荣耀
and that his sons and grandsons shall hold this honor
直到世界末日.
after him until the end of time.
( Lords mutter )
为取代叛徒艾德史塔克,
In the place of the traitor Eddard Stark,
国王陛下决定由泰温兰尼斯特,
it is the wish of his Grace that Tywin Lannister,
凯岩城主暨西境守护,
Lord of Casterly Rock and Warden of the West,
担任国王之手.
be appointed Hand of the King.
最后,
Lastly,
于此密谋四起, 动乱不堪之际,
in these times of treason and turmoil,
御前会议认为...
it is the view of the Council
乔佛里国王的生命安全
that the life and safety
of King Joffrey
实乃第一要务.
be of paramount importance.
巴利斯坦赛尔弥爵士.
Ser Barristan Selmy.
陛下, 我听候您的差遣.
Your Grace, I am yours to command.
请起, 巴利斯坦爵士.
Rise, Ser Barristan.
你可以卸下头盔了.
You may remove your helm.
长久以来你为国效命，尽忠职守.
You have served the Realm long and faithfully.
七国上下每个人都对你心怀感激.
Every man and woman in the Seven Kingdoms owes you thanks.
然而是时候让你卸下你的铠甲和宝剑了.
But it is time to put aside your armor and your sword.
你该安享晚年, 并自豪地回顾...
It is time to rest and look back with pride
你长久以来的功绩了.
on your many years of service.
( Murmuring )
陛下, 御林铁卫乃是宣誓效命的兄弟.
Your Grace, the Kingsguard is a sworn brotherhood.
我们必须终身守誓.
Our vows are taken for life.
惟有一死才能解除我们的神圣使命.
Only death relieves us of our sacred trust.
是谁的死, 巴利斯坦爵士? 是你还是你的国王?
Whose death, Ser Barristan? Yours or your King's?
我父亲的死就是你的责任.
Joffrey: You let my father die.
你太老了, 谁都保护不了.
You're too old to protect anybody.
- 陛下-- - 御前会议已经决定
- Your Grace-- - The Council has determined
由詹姆兰尼斯特爵士接替你的职务
that Ser Jaime Lannister will take your place
担任御林铁卫队长.
as Lord Commander of the Kingsguard.
那个人玷污了自己的宝剑
The man who profaned his blade
杀死了他宣誓要保护的国王!
with the blood of the King he had sworn to defend!
小心一点, 爵士.
Careful, Ser.
我们并非不知感恩
We have nothing but gratitude
您的长期贡献有目共睹, 爵士.
for your long service, good Ser.
您将得到一座坚固的海滨城堡,
You shall be given a stout Keep beside the sea,
以及满足您需要的大批仆役.
with servants to look after your every need.
给我一个养老的地方
A hall to die in
以及为我送终的人.
and men to bury me.
我既生为一名骑士.
I am a Knight.
也要死得像个骑士.
I shall die a Knight.
像个没穿衣服的骑士, 是吧.
A naked Knight, apparently.
( Laughter )
即便现在我仍可以像切蛋糕一样把你们五个通通砍倒!
Even now I could cut through the five of you like carving a cake!
拿去, 小子!
Here, boy!
把它熔了加到铁王座上吧.
Melt it down and add it to the others.
( Doors creak, clang )
如果在场各位还有其他事...
If any man in this hall has other matters
请现在向国王陛下禀报
to set before His Grace, let him speak now
否则退朝.
or go forth and hold his silence.
陛下.
Your Grace.
请上前来, 小姐.
Come forward, My Lady.
史塔克家族的珊莎小姐.
Steward: The Lady Sansa of House Stark.
珊莎, 你有事禀报国王陛下和御前会议?
Do you have some business for the King and the Council, Sansa?
是的.
I do.
启禀陛下, 我要为我父亲请求您的慈悲,
As it please Your Grace, I ask mercy for my father,
艾德史塔克大人, 前任国王之手.
Lord Eddard Stark, who was Hand of the King.
叛国大罪好似带毒的野草.
Treason is a noxious weed.
- 必须连根拔除... - 让她说下去.
- It should be torn out, root-- - Let her speak.
我要听听她的话.
I want to hear what she says.
感谢您, 陛下.
Thank you, Your Grace.
你要否认你父亲所犯罪行?
Do you deny your father's crime?
不, 诸位大人. 我明白他必须接受惩罚.
No, My Lords. I know he must be punished.
我请求的只是慈悲为怀.
All I ask is mercy.
我知道我父亲必定对其所为懊悔不已.
I know My Lord father must regret what he did.
他是劳勃国王的好友, 他敬爱国王.
He was King Robert's friend and he loved him.
你们知道他是真心敬爱他.
You all know he loved him.
他从未想当国王之手, 直到国王要求他.
He never wanted to be Hand until the King asked him.
他必定是受人蛊惑... 蓝礼大人或史坦尼斯大人
They must have lied to him-- Lord Renly or Lord Stannis
或是其他什么人. 他们欺骗了他!
or somebody. They must have lied!
他说我不是国王.
He said I wasn't the King.
他为什么要那样说?
Why did he say that?
他受了重伤.
He was badly hurt.
派席尔大学士给他服用了罂粟花奶.
Maester Pycelle was giving him milk of the poppy.
当时他神智不清. 否则他绝不会那样说的.
He wasn't himself. Otherwise h  never would have said it.
孩子对父亲的信赖... 多么单纯天真.
A child's faith... Such sweet innocence.
可是人们不是常说, 智慧之言往往来自
And yet they say wisdom oft comes
孩童之口么.
from the mouths of babes.
但叛国就是叛国!
Treason is treason!
你还有什么事?
Anything else?
如果您心里仍然有我,
If you still have any affection in your heart for me,
请成全我这个心愿吧, 陛下.
please do me this kindness, Your Grace.
你的肺腑之言感动了我.
Your sweet words have moved me.
但你父亲必须先俯首认罪.
But your father has to confess.
他必须承认我是他的国王...
He has to confess and say that I'm the King...
不然我无法手下留情.
Or there'll be no mercy for him.
他一定会的.
He will.
( Music playing )
== 翻译: freesand ==
== sync, corrected by elderman ==